<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technologiad</title>
    <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on technologiad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>STEM Musings #2: Towards New Coding Notation</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/github-sms-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/github-sms-notifications/</guid>
      <description>Test</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/resume/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/resume/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STEM Musings #2: Towards New Coding Notation</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/stem-musings-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/stem-musings-notation/</guid>
      <description>This is going to really be a musing given how short it is.
One of the most ubiquitous shibboleths in software is the use of the terms foo, baz (, and foobaz) as placeholders. They are not difficult to parse once you understand their purpose, but as notation goes its pretty bad. I’d prefer a formalization that echoes the terseness of Mathematical notation, while remaining intuitive. So far I’ve come up with these:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging The Data Divide</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/data-divide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/data-divide/</guid>
      <description>There’s a constant bifurcation between the technical and non-technical interaction with data, especially with databases. While developers work directly with the database via SQL, others are more comfortable using GUI based methods like spreadsheets. By default this excludes the notion of a global single source of truth. Since a database is the obvious candidate for this source of truth, the goal is to bring non-developers into the sphere of interacting with the database without having to learn SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STEM Musings #1: How Good Is CRUD As An Abstraction?</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/stem-musings-crud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/stem-musings-crud/</guid>
      <description>I do a lot of thinking about STEM - especially technology and engineering. It’s the building part where I trip up - hence the sparsity of blog posts. This series seeks to change through my putting my thoughts down without the need to have a tangible accompaniment.
Despite the global overview above my first topic is something that has a tangible component - as tangible as software can get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Keyboard As A Mouse</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/keyboard-as-mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/keyboard-as-mouse/</guid>
      <description>Announcement I’m moving towards writing reference articles for problems I’ve solved instead of saving links. This is the first of these.
 Summary Setting up a Raspberry Pi can be frustrating if you’re not prepared. On the manual route of flashing an SD card and navigating the alpha soup of cable connectors (USB Mini, USB C, HDMI to Mini HDMI), the other potential sticking points are the input and output devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmenting GitHub Stars Management</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/augmenting-starred-repos-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/augmenting-starred-repos-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Think of a piece of software you frequently use and a feature wishlist will likely follow. My list for GitHub mine includes custom tags for starred repositories. I am a simple man.
GitHub’s current support isn’t too shabby. There’s a language filter, three sorting criteria, and a decent search function which works with (creator supplied) tags. However, the inability to add my own tags to my 1500+ strong collection is the imperfection that ruins the experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Audio Books</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/auto-audio-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/auto-audio-book/</guid>
      <description>Ideas on my “Someday” list usually spend a couple of weeks before leaving forever or returning in disgrace (mine not its). “Can I automatically create an audiobook?” had a successful turn around of about three days.
The book I choose was Carroll Quigley’s “The Evolution Of Civilizations”. I’m at a point where I am militantly electronic with my reading, so the pdf link from Twitter was perfect. Skimming the book I got the sense that I’d prefer to listen rather than read it - a bifurcation that I recently adopted after ignoring audiobooks for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive As A Blogdown CMS</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/gdocs-cms-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/gdocs-cms-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>The true catalyst for this work is lost to the annals of time (known as September 2019), but bits and pieces surface from time to time. They include musings on the Jamstack, GitHub as a personal data store, concatenating different services, and, perhaps most importantly, how to combine these with a multi-user blogging site based on blogdown. Actually, I’m missing another important cause in the wish to have a traditional Content Management System to acccomodate those who aren’t familiar with markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income &amp; New York&#39;s Subway</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/income_nyc_subway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/income_nyc_subway/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My favorite data visualization is Inequality And New York’s Subway. It provides a fascinating look into the city via its main circulatory system. The information is a bit dated now (the data is from 2011), and I’ve always wanted to update it. However, navigating the US Census Bureau’s data portal always ended with me closing the tab in frustration.
My luck changed when Safe Graph released free neighborhood census data from 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microtransactions In Journalism</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/micropayments-journalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/micropayments-journalism/</guid>
      <description>The changing face of journalism has been written about extensively, which is unsurprising given the field’s major occupation. Advertistng driven revenue reached a peak of close to $50 billion dollars in about 2010 before being suffocated by the Google and Facebook juggernauts. Cue the shuttering of newsrooms and clearing of desks as the industry struggled to regain its footing in the digital age. Even new media companies who thought they had the nimbleness to avoid the fate of the old guard have stumbled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>handyman
[Repo]
A collection of personal Python Data Science scripts.
sansor
[Repo]
A collection of personal R Data Science scripts.
audiobook maker
[Repo]
A pipeline to convert pdfs (via OCR), plain text, or web articles to mp3s using Google&amp;rsquo;s Text to Speech API.
db ru
[Repo]
A prototype of a database frontend to allow non-technical users to Read and Update a database. It also included a log of the change to each cell to faciltate consistent reversion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Start</title>
      <link>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 15:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gfleetwood.netlify.com/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>After centuries of trying I finally mastered the art of blogdown. All it took was incremental version controlled changes and keeping git revert --hard close at hand. This is my third blog iteration after a Jekyll based version and Medium. They were both ill-equiped to handle Data Analysis heavy posts, so this setup is just right - especially after I figured out how to embed Jupyter notebooks in RMarkdown. For posteriority&amp;rsquo;s sake, here are links to Medium and RPubs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>